灰の雨
Ash rain?
いかん！ありゃ残され雲じゃ！
Oh no, it's "Nokosaregumo"!
すぐに嫁を！嫁をこしらえるんじゃ！
Hurry, prepare a bride. Quick!
その黒雲に名はなかった。
The black cloud had no proper name.
空にただひとつ残されたように浮かぶ姿から、
It floated over the land all alone,
as if left behind.
残され雲とだけ呼ばれていた
So the people often called it
"Nokosaregumo," the Forsaken Cloud.
Party is over
But I still wanna dance
I can't even sleep
Someday, one day my passion's fire will
From the beginning I knew
One day the flames would die out
Hey, I thought I didn't need anything
But even now, I'm so serious
Ah... I still have time to make it
Ah... but I'm gonna burn it up, baby
Sorry darling, it's not that easy
But surely it's not that bad either
Give me fire
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
Party is over
Sorry darling Hurry up
Ah... I still have time to make it
Give me fire
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
#8 The story of Saru
Ugh, it stinks.
くっせぇ～…
Like rotten eggs.
タマゴが腐った匂いみてぇ。
Doesn't it bother you?
あにきは平気なのか？
Can you even smell?
そもそも匂いってわかんの？
Jeez, I'm always the only one talking.
ちぇ～。おいらばっか喋ってさぁ。
You can talk now, can't you?
あにきだって喋れるようになったんだろ？
Okay, let's practice talking.
よし！おいらと話す練習だ。
Come on, say something to me.
さ！なんか話しかけてみてくれよ。あにき
Wow, a bridal parade.
へぇー。花嫁行列だ。
But...
でも…
Something doesn't seem right.
なーんか変だな…
Hey, stop that!
おい！ちょ、ちょっと待てよ！
Outta my way!
何すんだおめぇ！
No, I won't let you shoot arrows
at a happy bride.
そりゃこっちだ！めでたい花嫁に矢なんか飛ばしやがって！
What's wrong with you?
どういうつもりだよ
A happy bride? Yeah right! Big Sis is
being sent off to marry a monster.
めでたくなんかねぇ！姉ちゃんはなぁ、
バケモンの嫁になりに行くんだ！
To marry a monster?
バケモンの嫁？
So I gotta stop 'em.
だからおらぁが止めねぇと
Beat it! Or I'll shoot you too!
去ね！おめぇごと射んぞ！
Calm your horses. Tell me more about it.
まぁ待てって。よかったらその話聞かせてくれよ
We know a thing or two
about beating monsters.
おいらたち、バケモンにはちっとばかし縁があんだよ
That's it.
あれだ
A cloud right over the village.
That's the monster?
あそこだけ雲が浮いてら。あれがバケモン？
That's right.
そうだぁ。
Big Sis told me.
姉ちゃんが言ってた
People call it Nokosaregumo.
あいつぁ残され雲って呼ばれててな。
From way back in time, it's appeared
now and then to eat people up.
昔っからこの辺りに現れちゃあ人を食っちまうんだってよ
One time, the villagers offered a bride
to keep it from eating the others.
だから、これ以上人を食わねぇでくれって、
あるときバケモンに嫁をやったそうだ。
Then it left without killing any more.
そしたらおとなしく帰ってったんだってよ。
Ever since, they've offered a bride
every time it comes.
それから、現れるたんびに嫁をやったそうだ
If they don't offer one, it'll get mad
and eat up the whole village.
もし嫁をやらねぇと、怒って村ごと食っちまうんだ
It's a monster but it wants a human bride?
バケモンなのに人の嫁が欲しいのか？
And a lot of them, too?
それも何人も
Sis said it probably ate them all.
姉ちゃんは全員食われちまっただろうって言ってた
I'll never understand
how a monster thinks.
バケモンの考えることはよくわかんねぇなぁ。
So your big sis was chosen this time, huh?
で、今回はおめぇの姉ちゃんが選ばれたんだな？
I've got to help her.
I don't want her to be eaten up.
おらぁ姉ちゃんを助けてぇ。バケモンに食われちまうなんて嫌だ！
We can help you there.
そこでおいらたちの出番よ。
This guy here has beaten up
lots of monsters.
あにきはこれまでいろんなバケモンをやっつけてきたんだ
He can beat it for you.
あんな雲イチコロって！
-Really?
-But it's gonna cost you.
ホントか！？
-ただし、報酬はもらうけどな。
Can't do it for free.
タダ働きはしないんだ
They're great.
うめぇぞ
Not these.
Something worth money, you know?
こういうんじゃなくてもっと金になりそうなモンだよ
Hey, this is gold!
こりゃ砂金だ！
Got it in the river. I got lots of it.
川で拾ったんだ。そんな石ならいっぺぇあんぞ？
Take all you want.
欲しいだけやらぁ
Really? You've got a deal then.
ホントか？よし、取引成立。
I'm Dororo.
おいら、どろろ
I'm Saru.
おらぁ、さるだ
Saru? Like a monkey? That's funny.
さる？それが名前か？変なの
Dororo is a funny name, too.
どろろも変だー
No it's not, it's a nice name!
変じゃない！いい名前だろ！
Come on, say it's nice.
いい名前って言えよ！
It's not.
よくねぇから
Big Sis.
姉ちゃん！
I told you over and over not to come!
お前！あれだけ来ちゃいけねぇって！
I came to save you.
姉ちゃんを助けに来たんだ！
I can't leave with you.
行けないよ、私は
Why not?
なんでだ！
You're actually doing this
for the village?
もしかして…村のためか！
Forget about them!
あんなやつらほっとけ！
They're using you to save themselves.
自分らが助かるために姉ちゃんを差し出してよ！
That's not true.
違うよ
I chose to come.
あたしは自分から来たんだ。
I don't want any monster
eating everybody up.
バケモンなんぞにみんなを食わせたくなくてね
You, too.
お前だってそうさ
I don't want you to die.
おらは姉ちゃんに死んでほしくねぇ
I know. But you must leave.
いいからお逃げ
Hey, ease up.
まぁ待ちなって！
We'll beat that monster for you.
お姉さん、おいらたちがそのバケモンやっつけてやるよ。
That'll solve all your problems.
そうすりゃまるっと解決だ！
You? How will you defeat it?
あんたは…？それに、やっつけるってどうやって
If it eats people, it has to have
a mouth and a belly.
人を食うんならどっかに口とか腹とかあるはずさ。
We'll tear it apart.
そこをぶった斬るんだよ！
See? He's all ready for it.
ほら、あにきも任せろって
No. It's coming.
ちげぇよ…あいつが来たんだ！
W-What is this?
な…なんだこりゃ！
Let's get out of here!
い…今すぐ逃げとう…
Idiots, it'll hear you!
バカ！そんな大声出してると…
Hyakkimaru, over there!
あにき！あそこだ！
What's wrong?
あにきってば！どうしたんだよ！
Hyakkimaru's vision was surrounded
by a wall of evil flame.
百鬼丸の視界は一面炎に覆い尽くされていた。
The dark cloud was a part
of the devilish ghoul.
周囲に満ちる雲もまた、あやかしの一部だった。
Hyakkimaru was enclosed in a wall of fire.
炎の壁に包まれた百鬼丸は、
For the first time ever,
he had completely lost his sight.
何も見えないという状態を初めて知ったのだ
Big Sis!
姉ちゃん！
It's a centipede.
ありゃ、ムカデだ。
It's humongous.
とんでもねぇデカさだ
Hyakkimaru, it's coming!
あにき！来るぞ！
We're saved...
はぁ…た、助かった…！
This is where you live?
ここがさるの家か？
-Yeah, I live on my own.
-On your own?
そうだぁ。おらぁ1人で住んでる
1人？
Big Sis ain't my real sister.
姉ちゃんはおらぁの姉ちゃんじゃねぇ。
I've lived alone all my life.
おらぁずっと1人で生きてきたんだ
Papa and Mama died when I was real little.
父ちゃんと母ちゃんは、おらぁがちっせぇ頃に病で死んじまった
But I was fine.
でも平気だ
I had the mountain with me.
おらぁにゃ、山があったから
I hate humans.
人は嫌ぇだ
They said this wasn't my mountain
and drove me out.
ここはおらの山じゃなくなったってことや
おらを追い出すんだ
Stay away from me!
おらぁに近寄んな！
You're hurt. Let me see.
ケガしてるんだろ？見せてごらん
Are you the boy
that lives in the mountain?
あんたが山に住んでるって子かい？
You look like a saru, a monkey.
What's your name?
おさるみたいな顔やね！名前は？
Name?
名前？
You don't remember your name?
自分の名前、忘れちまったのかい？
Saru. My name's Saru.
さるだ。おらぁ、さるってんだ
It felt strange.
不思議だったぁ…
Just watching her made me forget
about hunger and cold.
あの姉ちゃんを見てるだけで、腹減ってんのも、さみぃのも気になんねぇ
Mama was the only one
who'd ever been kind to me.
おらぁに優しくしてくれたのは、母ちゃんだけだ
So I thought...
だからもしかして、
Maybe she was my mama once
sometime, in some place.
あの姉ちゃんはいつかどこかで
おらぁの母ちゃんだった人かと思いよったんだ
Your mama, huh.
おっかちゃん…か…
Saru, um...
さる…その…
I ain't got no time to cry.
泣いてるヒマなんかぁねぇやろ。
I gotta avenge Big Sis. Ain't I right?
姉ちゃんのカタキはおらぁが討たねぇと。そうだろ！？
Yeah, I never leave
a job half done, either.
あぁ！おいらだって一度受けた仕事は
最後まできっちりやるつもりだ！
Let's beat it together.
一緒にあいつをやっつけんぞ！
Yeah.
おぅ！
One thing, though.
ただ…な…
I don't know why, but Hyakkimaru
can't do anything when he's in that cloud.
理由はわかんねぇけど、あの雲の中じゃあにきは満足に動けねぇ
We'll have to do it on our own.
おいらたちだけであいつをなんとかしなきゃ
Has that cloud grown bigger?
ん？あの雲、前よりでっかくなってねぇか？
What's this?
あ…なんだ？これ…
It's his skin.
こらぁやつの皮だ！
This is bad. Centipedes get bigger
once they molt.
まじぃぞ、ムカデってぇのは脱皮すっとおっきくなんだ
Bigger? Even more than now?
おっきくって…あれよりもか？
Why? Isn't it supposed to go home
once it has a bride?
なんでだよ！嫁をもらったらおとなしく帰るんだろ？
It's mad about what we did to it.
昼間のことであいつも怒ってんのかもしんねぇ！
What do we do?
どうするよ！
Its weakness is sunlight.
はっ…あいつの弱点は日光だ。
If we lure it out of the cloud,
we can beat it.
からおてんと様の下に引きずり出せば倒せるはずだ！
Then I've got a good idea!
それならおらぁにいい考えがあんぞ！
Let's do it, Saru. We'll exterminate it.
やんぞ！さる！ムカデ退治だ！
Yeah, for my Big Sis.
あぁ！姉ちゃんの弔い合戦だ！
Big Sis... Big Sis...!
姉ちゃん…姉ちゃんよ…
Hey, this way!
やーい！こっちだ！こっち！
Size doesn't mean a thing.
ハッ！でかけりゃいいってモンじゃねぇ。
Try to catch me with those hundred feet.
その百本足でおいらを捕まえてみろ！
Come and get me!
こっちだ！こっち！
Almost.
そろそろだな…
Ouch...
ってぇ…
That was a close one.
あっぶねぇ…
Up to you now, Saru.
頼んだぞ、さる
This one is for Big Sis.
姉ちゃんのカタキだ…！
It doesn't burn in all that fire?
あんだけの炎でも燃えないのかよ…
Nah.
あぁ…
But don't worry.
でも問題ねぇ！
Melt away in the sun!
そのまま日の光にノビちまえ！
No way!
そんなぁ…！
Dang it, after all we did, still nothing?
ちきしょう…こんだけやってもダメなのかよ…
Hyakkimaru!
あにき！
He slashed it.
あにきが斬った！
What'd he just do?
何したんだ！？今！
Hyakkimaru had lost his sight
in the wall of fire.
炎の壁で視界を塞がれた百鬼丸は
So he'd located the monster
by listening to the arrow hitting it.
矢の当たる音であやかしの位置を確かめていたのだ
This is bad.
まじぃぞ！
That's it, sound.
そうだ！音だ！
Whatcha gonna do?
どうする気だ！？
Hyakkimaru, follow my voice!
I'm on its head!
あにき！おいらの声のするところがムカデの頭だ！
Is he calling for him?
もしかして…あいつを呼んでんのか！
Right here, Hyakkimaru!
Its eye is right next to me.
あにき！ここだ！おいらの横がこいつの目だ！
This is the end for you!
今度こそ終わりだ！
There's a head on the tail, too?
しっぽにも頭があんのか！
All right!
やったぁー！へへっ
Y'all okay?
大丈夫か！？
Never been better.
あぁ、このとおり
Big Sis?
姉ちゃん！
Big Sis!
Saru...
さ、る…
Yeah, it's me.
そうだぁ…さるだぁ…
I'm so glad you were alive.
姉ちゃん、生きててよかった…！
Hyakkimaru, is that...?
あにき？もしかして…
You got your nose back!
あにきの鼻が戻った！
Here's what I promised you.
さぁ！約束の報酬だ！
Yeah, thanks.
あぁ。ありがとよ
What are these?
なんだよ、この石…
Got lots of it around here.
この辺りによーく落ちてんだー！
No, I want gold.
おいらが欲しいのはこんな石じゃなくて砂金だって！
The shiny ones.
あの金ぴかの石！
I only had that little bit.
They're the same, right?
ありゃあれだけだぁ。おんなじようなモンだろ？
Aww, come on.
なっ…そ、そんな…
Thanks to you, I'm still alive.
Your name is...?
あんたたちのおかげで、死なずに済んだよ。えっと…
Dororo.
どろろ
Thank you, Dororo.
ありがとう。どろろさん
What are y'all going to do now?
あんたら、これからどうすんの？
We'll live together in the village.
村で一緒に暮らそうかって。
Since I'm all alone, too.
あたしも1人だから
-Good for you, Saru.
-Yeah.
-へぇ、よかったな！さる.
あぁ
Oh yes, we need to think of
a new name for you.
そうだ、名前！新しく考えないと
Saru's fine.
さるでいいよぉ
No, names are very important.
ダメ！名前は大事なんだから
You sound like you're really my sister.
なんだかホントの姉ちゃんみてぇだな！
Oh well.
まぁいっか！
Dororo...
ど…ろろ…
This sense is called smell, got it?
あにき、これはな…匂いってんだよ
Did you just say "Dororo"?
ん？今おいらのこと、どろろって…
It's the first time he said my name.
初めてだ、名前呼ばれたの
Hold up, bro!
あにきぃ！待ってくれよぉ！
My name's pretty nice, huh?
おいらの名前いい名前だろ！？
Sorrow scatters in the wind,
piling up to form shadows
Our footsteps admonish
indifference in such verbose ways
As I peek into your fathomless eyes,
I lose my composure
Is there any hope
in the place I am heading to?
I feign amusement and laugh
because this road is so dark
I will be there to shine the light
I'm used to playing at saying goodbye,
but I cried when I waved to you
Our fiery woes fade... and fade...
until night falls upon us
If I knew tomorrow would be so mundane,
I wouldn't have said that I wanted to live
I know it's futile but can't help dreaming
of a future... a future... you are to blame
"Nokosaregumo"